♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 8=
(I don't want to get married.)
(Will you take me away, Mr. Rong?)
Please don't take offense.
I spoiled Chun'er too much.
Don't worry.
I'll keep a close eye on her. She won't
run away from the wedding again.
Let's go to the main hall
for a cup of tea and a rest.
If Miss Jiang is unwilling,
I don't have to marry her.
- We might as well call it off now.
- Don't be rash.
The union between the Governor Mansion
and our family goes beyond this wedding.
Miss Jiang.
Mr. Rong.
I know the Governor pushed this match
only for the kingfisher phoenix crown
in Chun'er's dowry.
The kingfisher phoenix crown?
I think the Governor mentioned trading
the crown with the Xiaosheng Society.
So I hope in the future,
you'll be patient with Chun'er
and support the Jiang family.
The world is vast.
There's nowhere we can't go.
Just like in the opera,
we can go to river towns in the south
or deserts in the north.
I've got enough banknotes
to enjoy ourselves wherever we go.
Chun'er, life isn't like the opera.
Think it through.
I thought it through long ago.
I just want to know
if you are willing to be with me.
(I'm sorry, Chun'er.)
(I have something I must do.)
(I can only let you down.)
- If you're unwilling...
- Fine.
I'll help you.
(He'll kill me once he has the crown.)
(And he sent me to find Jade Buddha Head
just to squeeze the last use out of me.)
Young Marshal,
as you ordered,
all our men have been assembled.
No matter what happens,
we will ensure you get out safely.
What I want isn't to just get out safely,
but to hold my fate in my own hands.
Since he says I'm like him,
I'll grant his wish.
If he won't give me
the Governor's position, I'll take it.
Young Marshal,
we have too few men.
I'm afraid we can't rival the Governor.
If we don't fight now, we will die.
Understood.
You laughed at me for my unsteady hand.
It seems your shooting
isn't all that impressive either.
Then would you like to test my shooting?
I'm standing very close.
Let's see if I can hit you.
Let's try it then.
Drop your shoulder.
Push it forward.
It's not that hard.
Let's compete.
Sure.
♪A thousand sails gone♪
I hit it.
Draw.
Aim.
It's fine.
Again.
Draw.
Aim.
♪The boat waits in the wind and snow♪
♪Peach petals fall where dreamers go♪
♪The moon as before♪
♪A jug of wine in the night rain♪
♪Softly whispers♪
♪No return♪
♪No regret♪
Not that impressive.
You're so proud of defeating me,
a beginner at guns?
The person who can outshoot me
hasn't even been born yet.
♪I ask why♪
♪I yearn for the one who's gone
through heat and cold♪
The prize for you.
♪A handful of earth♪
♪The world's last gamble♪
♪Sighing at the late hour♪
♪No one comes to meet me♪
Xu You'an,
will you marry Miss Jiang?
Yes.
But you heard it too.
Xu Fan plans to kill you
after your wedding.
My life or death
doesn't depend on whether I marry.
Besides,
you seem to care quite a lot
about my marriage to Miss Jiang.
Since my master died,
she's the only one who's ever
given me everything for nothing.
I just hope everything
goes well for her.
What about your parents?
I've never met them.
Maybe I have, but I don't remember.
In my heart,
my master is my parent.
I once had a buddy.
And we only had each other.
Where is he?
After I joined the Rongqing Troupe,
I never saw him again.
I've searched for years
and never found a trace of him.
How many orphans in this chaotic world
got to live like I did?
I once had a buddy too.
When I finally found him,
he was already dead.
If he were still alive,
he would probably look just like you.
As long as Xu Fan lives,
he is a threat to everyone.
If you can't do it, I will.
(If there's a next life, may we
be free of all the entanglements.)
(We would surely share a drink
and become true friends.)
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪